To be continued...
He was an awful person. He had this story about the time in his life when he was someone important. He'd brag about it all the time. I remember it well because he made me listen to it every time. Every single time.
His insights had been expelled. But deep inside the cabin, there was an individual who still actually looked like a person. But he... He was not in any condition to talk.
The hell's this? Is it valuable or something?
That... That compass stands. It's there, the place where the compass stands straight up. It's there. A giant pit. A terrifying, wretched abyss that reaches to the bottom of the world.
I couldn't bear to look. I just couldn't. It's really there. The Golden City's there. It's true. It's inside the giant... The giant man-eating pit.
That's what the guy said. Then the old man just died on us. Anyway, pretty nice, right? And remember, you are nothing like me. Got it? Hold still.
I'm not like him with that boastful story he clung to. I prepared myself for that one purpose. For that one single thing.
No. No. No. I just knew I longed for it. A place. A place where no one knew me.
You know about the Golden City, right? They say it turns things to gold. Maybe even a worthless little thing like this. Or even a dirty, used-up girl. You think if I bring you two to the city, I can get rich?
I longed for a place where his voice, which still echoes even though he's gone, would finally vanish.
The journey is rough. No matter how much I trained, I'll never get used to being seasick.
It has already been 20 days since the last port of call. The fish we sometimes catch, and the booze that hasn't gone bad, are purely treats to us now.
Our leader, Razukyan, is once again eating raw bugs. He catches them down in the hold. He says it prevents disease.
Then there's the horizon. It constantly disappears. Only to show itself moments later.
Over and over again.
The only thing I have is plenty of nausea.
That's great.
It's not great at all.
Getting used to vomiting.
But the precious food...
Don't worry about it. We still have another month's supply of hardtack.
Besides, we're almost there.
To the spot where the star compass stands up straight.
And these uncharted seas and rough winds, it's the only thing we can trust.
But, uh...
Are you sure that it's alright for me to hold on to it?
Of course it is.
You're one of the revered three sages of Ganja now.
Besides, you're the one who brought me that compass in the first place.
Like it was some sort of destiny, you know?
Seriously, though, you're our guidepost on this journey before us.
Don't you worry.
My gut is always right.
We're almost there.
So, cheer up.
Anyway, I'm gonna go catch me some rats.
Don't mind him.
Belaf.
It's not that he's insincere.
I think you know that by now.
But sometimes he, and I guess that goes for the rest of us too,
just can't seem to put into words the truth he senses.
And that's why he can come off like that.
We didn't take him seriously at first because we thought it was all in his head.
But he's real.
Like he's touched by the divine.
In his case, even if the Golden City doesn't exist, he'll probably find it anyway.
Not to mention, he foretold that you'd join our group and become one of the three sages.
And that was the day right before you appeared.
Such is the power of his magnificent gift.
Yeah, but, Belaf, is it really okay for me to be one of the sages?
It's just that I don't have any sort of gifts like that.
What do you want me for?
I'm not worth trying to sell with this ugly body of mine.
The only thing I can do is take care of others.
Just what exactly do you think beauty is?
I don't know.
Oh, uh, is it something like you, Belaf?
Full of confidence?
That sort of thing?
I just don't know.
It is not beauty.
Just because it is beautiful.
It is not ugly.
Just because it is ugly.
Your...
Eyes sure are pretty.
There you go.
Beauty is in the eyes.
Understand?
Not the eyes in a physical sense.
Take it to mean...
The look they have.
Position, status, prestige, appearance...
And even confidence are not the true nature of beauty.
Even if your wounds fester,
Or you topple over in the face of injustice.
Even if you are forced down when you try to stand.
To continue.
To glare with affection and longing.
That look in the eyes is the true nature of beauty.
You have eyes full of darkness.
Affix your eyes upon that darkness.
For the light that no one else has found can only exist in the true void.
And remember, you are more capable and lovely than you can imagine.
Very much so.
So no matter how dirty or unsightly, my eyes will not be deceived.
Keep that in mind and trust yourself.
Wicco, we need you to come inside.
Sumasura has a fever.
Okay, I'll be right there.
Uplifting as always.
Did you call her dirty?
No, whatever.
You know I was just trying to take a deeper look into things.
How are the others doing?
Jomi's and R's are the only ones still afloat.
Wazukyan, look!
That cargo's from Jomi's hold.
I fear that means they're gone.
Hey, Bella, Wazukyan!
Look at the compass!
Huh?
What is that?
Land in an impassable patch of sea.
It's gotta be!
I wanna know where the people are
I take my dreams to life
Okay, who wants to be the first ashore?
All right, we are finally here
Where our new lives begin
Let it echo far and wide
To the people of our abandoned homeland
Yours are the feet that will crush injustice
It's really here
Yes, it is
To the one
And I know where I belong
Go to guard
Who will the place
Because if you have a forever
But you will use your house
Let as of your behalf
Who will play
Like my hai
What is that such?
Now that we are of course
Look at me
From Gerson
How does Gerson
Go to Gerson
How
Do.....
Soc
He's saying
Um, Mozu-hyon, these people were not mentioned in our intel.
Ha ha ha!
What the?
Ah, yeah. This is the real thrill of an adventure.
Ah, what strange cliffs. Is this here the giant pit?
How's it going?
It would seem those who came before us were violent and domineering, so they're reluctant to share information.
Ah, haji! Haji!
What is it? What's that guy saying and why is he pointing at me?
Kephu, kefu!
Precious, you say?
Kephu, risore!
He says it's a precious thing.
Korusomu!
Essential part?
Hajime korusomu, Guko.
It looks like he's telling us that he's willing to help us out in exchange for the compass.
Here you go.
Are you sure about this?
I mean, you've had your gaze on it for so long.
It's what guides you.
It's fine, really.
The object of my gaze lies within the darkness.
Uh, Borlaff, I... I want to... I need to go looking for it.
That light that no one else has found yet.
It's so big.
Can there really be people living in a place like this?
That's insane.
The Golden City.
The natives have told me that they call this place Shoro.
And that means?
The capital of the unreturned.
They also said you'll never be able to come back, but that the city does exist.
What's going on?
Um, well, this little kid, it seems that she followed us all the way here.
Uh, wha? Why is she sniffing me?
Excuse me a moment.
Uh, wha?
Ah!
This tattoo.
These wounds are still fresh.
An infant.
Impossible.
As she cannot bear children, she is hereby exiled to the Giant Pit.
That's roughly what it says.
That sounds so horrible.
We don't have spare resources to keep her safe.
Yeah, well, she's from here, though.
She might know a lot about the pit.
Besides them.
Not only that.
Just look at her, you guys.
She's kind of adorable.
What's your call, Wazukyan?
Hmm.
Well, we're in terrible need of a guide.
One less thing to worry about.
Can't really see down into the pit too well from here, I'm afraid.
One second.
I'll climb up.
What is it?
What the hell?
What's this?
Poison?
Mayazuma, Kurohomachi.
Mayazuma, Zomu.
Sorry.
I don't understand what you're saying.
She's saying, if you ascend within the interior, you will be eaten.
Hmm?
By what?
Zomu.
The closest translation would be, the curse.
See?
We really do need a guide, don't we?
I'm counting on you.
Now let's go, shall we?
To the city!
It's not like I was feeling triumphant or anything.
But my pulse was racing like it never had before.
We were Gonja, a group of outcasts that set out for the Golden City.
We had been forsaken by our homelands.
Believing in a nameless god, we roamed searching for its source, and in those who were no longer human.
We found paranormal relics, otherworldly scenery, and the curse.
Everything had all the mystery we'd been hoping for.
All the intensity we had been searching for.
So surely, the source of all this wonder, must be here too.
Whoa.
Hey!
B worked!
Wow!
I can see outside!
Bigger than I thought and it's so quiet too hard to believe we're in a whirlpool
This smell though, I recognize it there must be some eternal fortune incense in here
Maybe so cave raiders burn it for celebrations and even funerals sometimes
It smells like someone is burning it fresh
I bet that bastard Bondrood lights them every once in a while. Yeah Bondrood. What was that guy after down here?
Anyway, who knows doesn't seem like it's simply reaching the bottom of the netherworld though
He said something about the next two thousand years
Well, I sure don't feel like going back and asking him everything. He says is laced with poison
No doubt anything. He'd tell us would be self-serving
Yeah, let's focus on what's next instead. We've had enough of that creep
Honestly, I just want to be genuinely happy about continuing on with you guys down to the bottom of the netherworld
No, no, no gee
Nah, it is annoying that he can still peek in on my vision, but I guess the good news is that's all he can really do to us now
So then let's show him our big grand adventure
I'm glad to see you thinking positively
You purposefully snuck up on me didn't you rag?
Don't sniff me
How'd he do that? I didn't even hear him coming
It's it's moving
It's going down
Um, I just rubbed Prushka a bit and I think I felt something
Uh, uh
Adventures have a strange way of suddenly getting started, you know
Riko, don't mess around with the Prushka stone
Wouldn't be very funny if we started going up instead
Yeah, sorry
Uh, Riko, Nanachi, what's that?
Even the letter didn't mention that thing
You think maybe it's some sort of fish
What is this?
I think it's bones and corpses that have been frozen stiff
The sea of corpses
The name makes more sense now
Yeah
They say that the souls returned to the bottom of the netherworld
But it's as if they're told to leave their bodies behind
To be honest with you guys, I didn't actually think we'd ever get this far
Well, I knew we would make it
Sure is taking a while to get there
Yup
It's been quite some time since we passed by that layer of corpses
You remember how many meters it was on the map?
Hey, Riko!
Come over here for a second
Mania's taking a dump on this altar
Kinda looks important
Irredeemable
And disrespectful too
I hope you feel better, Mania
Yeah, so
Tell you the truth
I don't think I'll be able to hold it all in either
You gotta take a pee?
Both?
You can't hold it until we get out of this thing?
I don't really think so
Didn't we learn back in class that many cave raiders end up losing their lives while having to relieve themselves?
Riko, there is no telling what awaits us
Just do the deed here
Luckily, there's still the smell of incense
It's so quiet
You can hear it quite clearly
Bondrewd, you seeing this?
If you weren't you, I might feel kind of bad for you right now
Oh, there's something below
There's something below
Ah
The place where the compass stands on its end
The golden city everyone seeks
Everyone longs for
And dreams of
Indeed
It was really there
Oh wow
Ah
At last
We had finally arrived
And then
We were never again
Able to return
Art
At last
Give me a win
A home
A long way
We were so afraid
Thank you.